<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools">
    <string name="app_name">Reading Anxiety Project</string>
    <string name="M1">Coyotes and wolves are both types of wild canines native to the United States. They are related. In some parts of the country, they have mixed to create a sub species called coywolf. While coyotes and wolves are similar animals, they are also different in many ways. While wolves once inhabited much of North America, they are now limited to wilderness areas. In the meantime, coyotes have spread from the western half of the country to the Southeast and Northeast.</string>
    <string name="M2">Unlike wolves, they do well living around humans and can even be found in cities. On average, wolves are much larger than coyotes. Coyotes have sharper ears and noses, while wolves have more rounded ears and bigger noses. While coyotes\' fur tends to be gray or brown, wolves can be grey, white, red, or black. Coyotes can run faster and longer than wolves. Both wolves and coyotes live in family units that include a mother, a father, and puppies. Coyote packs may expand temporarily to include unrelated adult and young coyotes for hunting, but wolf packs usually contain many families. Wolves hunt in packs to kill very large prey like bears or elk. Coyotes hunt in pairs and eat smaller prey such as rabbits, mice, and reptiles, though they may sometimes cooperate with other adults to kill larger mammals.</string>
    <string name="M3">Unlike wolves, coyotes will also eat fruits and vegetables. Coyotes and wolves are both important in Native American stories. Wolves usually symbolize strength and loyalty. Often, coyotes play the part of a trickster or one who breaks the rules in clever ways. Wolves and coyotes are similar animals, but subtle differences in behavior and living conditions make them different species.</string>
    <string name="N1">Soda, pop, soft drink, cola, seltzer -- these are all different names for the same drink that many people enjoy today. Whatever you call it, fizzy water has a unique history! What makes soda water unique is the carbonation. The carbonation comes from carbon dioxide. You may have heard of carbon dioxide before in science class. It is the chemical that people exhale when breathing. It is also the chemical that plants use as food. Companies add carbon dioxide to water through extreme pressure to make soda or seltzer water. But now you can make fizzy water at home, too. Hundreds of years ago, soda water was sold at pharmacies as a remedy. People believed that this fizzy water would solve all types of health problems. Pharmacists would mix the bubbly water with other drugs and flavors for their patients. We now know that soda water has no real health benefits.</string>
    <string name="N2">Although there is no real benefit from soda water, people grew to love the feel of the bubbles on their tongue. Now, soda water is popular around the world for non-medical reasons. Soda water is the same regardless of how it is used, but there are many different flavors that you can add to soda water. Originally, pharmacists would add flavors like lime, cherry, or even coffee to soda water. One of the first best selling flavors of soda was Dr. Pepper. Another early flavor was Coca-Cola. Coca-Cola was originally promoted to have health benefits that would restore strength. We now know that these claims are false. </string>
    <string name="N3">Companies aren\'t allowed to make false claims like this anymore. (Sometimes they still make false claims and can be sued.) Another problem with flavored sodas is that they contain a lot of sugar, which can lead to other health problems. Because of the health issues associated with too much sugar, cola companies started making diet versions of their soda. The first diet soda was a sugar-free ginger ale. Other diet sodas quickly came to market. Diet sodas have increased in popularity ever since. Today, however, many people are trying to choose healthier drinks such as tea, unflavored soda water, or even just plain water.</string>
    <string name="O1">My great-uncle Bradford and my great-aunt Marianne lived in a tin-roofed cabin on the sunny side of a steep hill. Throughout the county, they were renowned for the prize-winning vegetables their garden patch produced. One year, they grew a pumpkin as large as a five-year-old child is tall. Every spring, the neighbors came to beg for some of their tomato seeds, but, even using their seeds, no one grew tomatoes as deeply red and juicy as my great-aunt and uncle did. Some said it was luck that accounted for their success. Some swore Bradford was spraying his plants with some secret chemical formula. Bradford said it was his fiddle-playing on moonlit nights that caused the garden to flourish. Marianne always said, with a mysterious smile, "You just have to know how."</string>
    <string name="O2">One summer, at the end of August, when Bradford and Marianne were out in the garden with their harvesting baskets, Marianne discovered an enormous zucchini hiding under some leaves. It was much too large to fit in her basket. It was already bigger than a newborn baby. Well, let\'s just see how big it gets, Marianne said to herself. A week later, when they went to check on the zucchini, it was the size of a year-old piglet. Bradford wanted to bring it in, but Marianne convinced him to leave it on the vine just a little bit longer. The following week, it was the size of a young calf. Then, it was the size of the calf\'s cud-chewing mother.</string>
    <string name="O3">Finally, in October, they decided to pick it before the frost came. By then, it was the size of a recreational vehicle. Its growth had already knocked down the garden fence, and it was starting to threaten the side of the house. It took an axe to chop the stem, and two men on a cross-cut saw to slice the gigantic vegetable into manageable pieces. Marianne cut some pieces into slivers, which she put up in a pickle brine, and some other chunks she put into a wood chipper and used the pulp for zucchini bread. Here\'s my theory: the garden sits on a spot where an asteroid fell to earth, and the vegetables are nourished by extraterrestrial minerals.</string>
    <string name="P1">Crows are scavengers. The birds will eat almost anything, from vegetables and fruit, to nuts and seeds. They\'ll devour insects, frogs, lizards, mice, smaller birds, basically any animal they can fit into their mouths. And they\'ll happily pick at the flesh of carrion, which probably accounts for why ancient people associated crows with death. Crows are playful birds, very sociable with their own kind, and they live in large extended family groups. They frequently indulge in silly games, such as carrying a twig high into the air, dropping it, then quickly swooping down and catching it. They\'ve also been observed executing acrobatic backflips in flight.</string>
    <string name="P2">Though few species of crows migrate, very often, during the fall and winter months, the birds will congregate in large groups, known as roosts. These roosts may range from a few dozen crows to hundreds of thousands. One astonishingly large roost, recorded in Oklahoma, was estimated at over two million crows. Exactly why they gather in such large groups remains a mystery, though researchers suspect that the birds congregate for protection against predators, as well as to communicate with one another and exchange information about where to find food. Nearly all ornithologists (from the ancient Greek words ornis "bird" and logos "explanation") agree that crows are vastly intelligent creatures, with large brains in relation to their body size.</string>
    <string name="P3">Their intelligence is near the top of the avian world, alongside that of parrots. Their brains, at least in scale, are larger than human brains. A human brain is about one-and-a-half percent of body mass, while the brain of an American crow is more than two percent of its body mass. And like us, crows are toolmakers. For example, they\'ll use straight twigs to poke for grubs, and then use a hooked twig to pull the grub from its hiding place. Crows often drop nuts onto roads and rocky surfaces to crack them open. In Japan, the clever birds deposit walnuts at intersections, placing the nuts right in front of the wheel of a car. Then, after the car crushes the nut, the crows return to peck at the pieces.</string>
    <string name="Q1">Societies tend to function best when there are well-defined laws. Yet, even more important than the laws are the people who get to decide, enact, and enforce those laws. The people and structures that make those decisions are called government. Worldwide there are many types of government. These function at local, regional, and national levels. In all instances, government is the basis of power and control. But even when power is shared among people, problems arise. So, no form of rule is perfect.</string>
    <string name="Q2">An aristocratic government is power and control in the hands of a few people. Usually these people are thought to be different from the general population in some way. Ways in which aristocrats are thought to be different include: wealth, physical strength, intelligence, honor, technology, or achievement. A despotic government is absolute power and control in the hands of a single person or very small group. Despotic rulers often rule out of self-interest and ignore the desires of the people. They often come to power in one of two ways. First, they can inherit power from a relative—such as a king or queen. These are known as absolute monarchs or dictators. Second, a despotic government can seize power from their predecessors. This process is called a military coup. Often despotic governments are authoritarian or totalitarian. This means that the person or people in power try to control all aspects of life.</string>
    <string name="Q3">A democratic government is one in which people are involved in decision making. There are two main ways democracies function. One is direct democracy where people get to create, vote on, and enact laws on their own. The other is indirect democracy where citizen elect politicians to vote on and enact laws. Often in democracies a simple majority wins, but this can put people with minority viewpoints at a disadvantage. Anarchy is the opposite of government where a population is not ruled by any controlling body. In some senses, people view anarchy as disorder due to the lack of laws. However, for proponents of this form of "government", it removes all power structures. It makes individuals truly equal because it removes power from those with wealth, strength, merit, military arms, honor, and technology.</string>
    
    <string name="M">Coyotes and Wolves</string>
    <string name="N">Fizzy Water</string>
    <string name="O">Prize Winning Vegetables</string>
    <string name="P">Crows</string>
    <string name="Q">Government</string>
    <string name="defaultspinnertext">Select a story</string>



</resources>